<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
  <title>Obachuka</title>
  <link>http://obachuka.com</link>
  <description>Obachuka's personal website</description>
  <atom:link href="http://obachuka.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <language>en</language>

  <item>
    <title>Too slow</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/29/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I started following Andrew Loomis's <i>Figure Drawing For All It's Worth</i>. Apparently, it's <i>the</i> book for figure drawing. I did these in less than an hour.</p> <img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/V94-A8VCPZ3kNfPbWNo9__RUw0asC8c6417XQgxjxJi2JDD1LCl53VhgxpR-jE-tdCxnT6v6k-nh=w1074-h803-no"> <p>Honestly, I'm not making enough progress. Even if I make this a habit and practice every day, an hour of practice isn't enough to get where I want to be. Let's say outside of work, sleep, eating, and miscellaneous, I have around 4-6 hours of free time. I need to be making the most of that time, not just an hour. I will have to cut the internet out completely; it's a waste of time. I also have roughly 2-3 hours in the morning before I go to work. But I take too long to do anything productive; it takes me an hour just to fully wake up. That's too long. I need to get better sleep. I've tried a lot of things to get better sleep, but really, I just need to be more rigorous about my sleep schedule. I've been getting up at 6am this entire week so far, so I'm off to a good start, but now I just need to maintain it.</p> <p>Back to the drawings themselves, they're completely off. But I think the lengths are mostly right, I need to get the widths more accurate next. The first chapter in the book is all about proportion, so that's what I'm trying to focus on. The thing that will help me most though, is more practice.</p> </body>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/29/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Jacking up blog post count</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/28/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I didn't write a blog post this morning. Once I slip up once, I tend to procrastinate more. I need to be stricter about going to bed on time, and to finish something in the morning before work. Because once work starts, I'll be too lazy afterwards to do anything. And if I'm tired, I'm slower at work at get home later and go to bed later. It's a vicious cycle.</p> <p>I almost considered just skipping today and picking it back up first thing tomorrow, but I forced myself to do <i>something</i>. What did I do?</p> <p><a href="https://github.com/obachuka/zuzu/commit/57666b076489b10ebbd2d0d811c61e715cce0017">I renamed my C structs to use lower_case capitalization</a></p> <p>Pretty pointless, I admit. It's like cheating on your NanoWrimo word count. But I want to do this more to build up that habit than anything else. This blog if focused on quantity, not quality.</p> <p>And besides, lower_case naming seems more C-like. I already know the object will be a struct or a union, because I won't typedef it. It felt weird having everything being lower_case ExceptForStructs. And I don't like typedef'ing in general. I never understood the point of abstraction, it always made things less clear to me. Whenever I looked through library code that made extensive use of typedef's, I'd just end up searching for the definition of that typedef. Then that'll also have a typedef, so I'd search that up too. Blegh.</p> <p>I'm sick of the way I code at work, with tons of abstraction, classes, and configuration. That's why I used C instead of C++: no classes. My code will probably end up with tons of anti-patterns.</p> <p>Yeah whatever.</p>
]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/28/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Still not ready? Figures...</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/27/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I've wanted to draw characters for a long time now, but I don't know anything about anatomy. I didn't even know how to draw. So I practiced my lines, my boxes, my perspective, my forms, my shading. It was never good enough.</p> <p>Saying "never good enough" makes me sound like a perfectionist, slaving for hours over my drawings. On the contrary, I put minimal effort into them. I just got bored of still life. I used pencil and a massive canvas (or at least, felt massive to me). Shading things the right value with that tiny pencil nib took forever. It was a tedious process, and just not very fun.</p> <p>I wanted to do people, I wanted to do imaginaray landscapes. But I wasn't ready.</p> <p>I've thought about making this blog for a while now, to chronicle my learning progress, so that one day should I ever be successful, I can point others to this meager blog and tell them the tale of my journey. But I wasn't ready! I haven't got anything to show off! I haven't learned anything worth sharing!</p> <p>And so the months went by and nothing happened. Then one day I bought my domain, and that was it.</p> <p>Today, I spent ten minutes doing gesture drawings with poses, with the <a href="http://www.posemaniacs.com">posemaniacs website</a>.</p> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/KGcyHVq.png"> <p>I'm quite proud to say, it was a complete failure.</p> ]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/27/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Hello world with Emscripten and SDL2</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/26/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I tried my hand at compiling C to Javascript using Emscripten. I had trouble getting Emscripten ports working using the default version that comes on Ubuntu 16.04, so I had to build the latest version from source. Xenial Xerus released this year, and it's still out of date.</p> <p>I created a color changing window you can view <a href="http://obachuka.com/zuzu/2016//06/26/zuzu.html">here</a>. The goal is to eventually create a game that also runs in the browser. I hate creating stuff for the web, but I also hate downloading stuff from sites I don't trust. So as the user, I appreciate web ports.</p> <p>I should note that I compiled the color changing window without any optimization flags. It wouldn't work on Chrome when I used them, but they did on Firefox. I'm assuming it's because Chrome hasn't fully implemented asm.js or something else like that. But I want everything I put on the web to work on both Chrome and Firefox.</p> <p>To hell with anything else.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/26/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Practicing brush control</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/25/</link>
    <description>Apparently I did my RSS description wrong or something.</description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/06/25/</guid>
  </item>

</channel>
</rss>
