<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
  <title>Obachuka</title>
  <link>http://obachuka.com</link>
  <description>Obachuka's personal website</description>
  <atom:link href="http://obachuka.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <language>en</language>

  <item>
    <title>Fat Dot Thanksgiving update</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/11/24/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Happy Thanksgiving! This year, I'm thankful for being the most awesome guy I know. To celebrate my inflated ego, I gave Fat Dot an update.</p><p>This is a gameplay change this time. The way you play the game is still the same, but I made shrinking easier to understand, as in you now shrink automatically. The boundary's behavior was changed to end and score your combo. This change came about because I didn't like how the clicking behavior changed when an existing combo was already in progress. Plus, some players wouldn't regularly shrink themselves. The game is a bit easier now that the shrinking is automatic, but you still have to decide whether or not you want to continue your combo. A side effect of this update means that you can now extend your combos further by starting another explosion. I think there's more strategy this way.</p><p>That said, it's hard to know the actual outcome of this update, because I haven't really play tested it. And since I don't have any sort of testing (who needs that?), it's hard to tell if I introduced any bugs. It's been a while since my last update here, and coming back to my code after a few months, I noticed there were side effects everywhere. Any small change could result in a bug. I started out my code with the intention of violating several best practices, and it was fun to code differently from when I code for work.</p><p>So if you find any bugs, let me know. Love y'all.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/11/24/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Converting height to normal maps</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/27/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>For my next game, I want to experiment with my own 2D rendering. I'll need normal maps for what I'm planning, so I wrote my own small little converter to transform height maps to normal maps. I know programs already exist that can do this for you, but I wanted to try my own hand at it. I stole the following height map of a volcano from the internet somewhere.</p> <img src="http://www.pontov.com.br/site/images/stories/artigos/Criando-terrenos_124C4/volcano.png"/> <p>Here is the result:</p> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/NKLfPFF.png"/> <p>Red is the x axis, with full red pointing to the right, and green is the y axis, with full green pointing up. All vectors are normalized, with blue pointing outwards to the viewer. Looking at other people's normal maps, these look correct, but I won't actually know until I use them to render.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/27/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Flat figures in perspective</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/21/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Just following along with Loomis.</p> <img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/samkXsdB1i1GQ3967gL1gh8PJrqO0ToqsFPUCcZqfmFccqfhUKxkkgXSyzAwau6V4iVZi31c5RoCcb81P4rvrk2jZLZmWTm-3pHM88PRW66C-8MBdfY7xX-OZ9uA0dz4W-n2me6eqXoVMFW89jj-VhiCVaHmO6iN9QGIMmnJAd2LyovJjedEivmxhyXwFLZA-MQXipFCh6dsKyRyBgYLi7Wbhu7iT-s0hOi6NMn1echjegxQuF8vV6_9AFa3qP6h0uxQHSvHEt0VQCbx1ldt-KC5N06qb_Im9BPZwJN8FY9m0RHEC1EYbGLBi1aQcf3RQwJUQ9CLl9z7h4mnJmfvx4DLbO9jq9QvMFUWSKGAM1P-zEZsR79s3txZQjHNOv67VlmFAmPqGThXTO5vgF1RywB3zJd9fP_frT0DI-XJH4xr8DHmVjvVEfbtKBZ-oDZX3MtOMuOaJqIOpci-jPYkIiTWwLa1QNl0u7CNZBGbOcTVRsutkHGAkDw1warWTqI-g4x4K1v4pCj3Dh9RyBIprcTnv5Q_jbFiAAqYh_2OQW8pR-Kzr9aG5BrBO128lwoq33q9PNu6ZBCReUCBng2jD5NbHMByqyc=w1805-h1350-no">]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/21/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Heights of children</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/18/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Tried figure outlines at different heights, this time using proportions of men at different ages.</p>
    <img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/TtWCnGOH0q3BiL8hHCh2PG3j3Y-rzHhYBk-OTvGvbjMRkjQVnuCCStwLRttWMvRrLSI7BWG6ciGvMcIVxYOMvWxfEuhJVaQDadpN791DS_JJrvF3D9X6g0IEnk1i9A30qS6eJVUahdBLuUVI8_aLaQysEy6S7GXItNvsGAepqZdDwhjQnP_VopgDwnM3SY6x3hx9Vycm3p0h9fsWiZ3uhzRioxG-Yk1rux7VLCjzsa8rS2m3C8FIjdVMC_CXBZlcMgRQtJildkVZdKavhZsKmOVQJojuWPiSVjL9bGVr-ulOpP8zCnWjuJ6F_-1CFHFo4HOwaHUNqDQ5Su20VXubq0cZ4oPnzJRXUMBPmFACf9WW4HyCRej6_o9R4brGAmpAHqeNR6n2EpM48KgHOD2dHUOebOOlkRRyTSMzRt6PUc5HUvD4CP6IfiwbaLWMOmLkPeiFvFUlcR9JshLnqHDTtW2j3Gw7e6zbr3G5kqSss0PwYvEG4W4wOCwtOtPBHzFDPY1sh2HWwbyrzGJ9v5BVAqBSgsXxMzC_YuMtb0uuhzRSGTRTs0h7eTqcn8eq9lhkE1wE_3eQkm9vCN2wn-L9vMhvl4p8ao8=w1805-h1350-no">]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/18/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Practiced more figures</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/15/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I practiced drawing; more of the same really. I wonder if there's any point in updating every day. It's just me saying, "Hey. Check me out. I did something today."</p> <p>Maybe I should get rid of the rss feed. This is really just a way to hold me accountable; people shouldn't actually be reading these low effort posts.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/14/</guid>
  </item>

</channel>
</rss>
