<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
  <title>Obachuka</title>
  <link>http://obachuka.com</link>
  <description>Obachuka's personal website</description>
  <atom:link href="http://obachuka.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <language>en</language>

  <item>
    <title>UI improvements</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/01/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I made some text updates, so hopefully it's more clear how to play the game. I said I wasn't going to add any more feautures, but I got so much done today, that I figured I could go ahead and add sound. It took me six hours, and sound still doesn't work. It's infuriating. I hate sound. Anyways, play the newest version <a href="http://obachuka.com/FatDot/0.2.1/fat_dot.html">here</a>.</p> ]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/08/01/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Beta release</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/31/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I didn't make a post yesterday, but I won't count that as missing a day because I actually did a lot of work yesterday. As of today, my game is gameplay complete. It's still missing sound, and I want to fix a few UI problems and other bugs. But I consider those minor changes. There won't be any dramatic changes in the game from here. <a href="http://obachuka.com/FatDot/0.2.0/fat_dot.html">Check it out here</a>.</p> ]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/31/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Improved fonts</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/29/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://obachuka.com/FatDot/0.1.1/fat_dot.html">Check out my better font rendering!</a> So it turns out I was just being stupid about my fonts. All my complaints were all easily addressed, I was just too lazy to look, since I wanted to get it done quick.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/29/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>First alpha</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/28/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://obachuka.com/FatDot/0.1.0/fat_dot.html">Here's my first version of the game!</a> It's only been tested on Chrome and Firefox. Any other browser is on their own. Input doesn't work on mobile phones either.</p> <p>There's still a bunch of bugs in this release, and I couldn't get text rendering working either, so I'm printing it to the console output. As I've said before, I want to replace my font code anyways.</p> <p>I want to give a shoutout to <a href="http://lyceum-allotments.github.io/">John Sharp's blog</a>. Emscripten has a lot of documentation, but for some reason, I could not find the basic usage instructions. And this guy has it all neatly compiled together on his blog.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/28/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Reberu</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/27/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Here's a gif of one of the higher levels. Random sizes and spiky dots.</p> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/JOtM65L.gif"> <p>There's a glitch in this image. A red dot trespasses through the explosion fine without any repercussion. It seems to happen only with large explosions, so it's probably a glitch with my quadtree.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/27/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Invincible spikes</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/26/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I introduced invincible spikes today. Spikes means a dot is invincible, while a gray outline means that a dot <i>can</i> turn invincible.</p> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/bjTq8YL.gif"/> <p>The player dot uses the same spikes and outline to denote when the player is attacking and when the player is ready to attack.</p> <p>I made invincible dots to introduce a different type of difficulty in later levels. That's right, my game will have levels. Levels is my last "necessary" feature before I am willing to say my game is in a finished state.</p> <h3>Here are my remaining required tasks:</h3> <ul> <li>Levels</li> <li>Compile to Windows 10</li> </ul> <h3>Here are my remaining optional tasks:</h3> <ul> <li>Sound</li> <li>Purple dot</li> <li>Saving high scores</li> <li>Power up pick up</li> <li>Better font rendering</li> <li>Hard mode</li> <li>Compile to OS X</li> </ul> <h3>Here are tasks I've given up on finishing:</h3> <ul> <li>Use OpenGL directly</li> <li>Animation</li> <li>Music</li> </ul> <p>The reason I put "levels" above something like "sound" is because my game is honestly quite boring without it. It might have been the primary reason my game was fun. I'll go into more detail when I actually make the levels.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/26/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Home stretch</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/25/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I didn't work on my game today, but I'll still consider it a success. I reset my sleep schedule, started exercising again, and now I'm going to bed before 10PM.</p> <p>I still feel like there's so much to do, but this is my last week. Whatever I have at the end of this week, I'm publishing it. Just a bit more to do. I've published my code <a href="https://github.com/obachuka/FatDot">on GitHub</a> if you want to see the dumb stuff I did to get it all working.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/25/</guid>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>SDL blending modes</title>
    <link>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/23/</link>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>So SDL only offers four blending modes: no blending, alpha blending, additive blending, and multiplicative blending. They don't have subtraction or division. Take a look at their alpha blending formula on their <a href="https://wiki.libsdl.org/SDL_BlendMode">documentation</a>. In case their documentation changes in the future, I'll spell it out here.</p> <blockquote>dstRGB = (srcRGB * srcA) + (dstRGB * (1-srcA))<br>dstA = srcA + (dstA * (1-srcA))</blockquote> <p>Note that this blending is not transitive, and the order you render transparent objects matter. I've been using unordered arrays in my code for O(1) deletes. This causes my objects to render in a different order when something is removed from the array.</p> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/qAoYtv6.gif"> <p>You can see the rendering errors happen most visibly in the upper left. To get around this, I use additive blending for my explosions. Any color added to white (the background color) is still white, so before rendering the color of every explosion, I render a black circle. The results look quite interesting. This is the only solution I can think of without calling OpenGL, which I don't think I can do if I want to finish this game by next week.</p> <img src="http://i.imgur.com/Ua76c12.gif"> <p>I need to clean up the textures a bit, but I think this looks better.</p>]]></description>
    <guid>http://obachuka.com/2016/07/23/</guid>
  </item>

</channel>
</rss>
